my name is Joe Brewer and imma change
strategist today I want to share with
you another book that I think is really
helpful for trying to create large scale
social change the book i'm going to
review today is this one that big pivot
radically practical strategies for a
hotter scarcer and more open world by
andrew Winston this is a book for anyone
who's trying to change the business
world as you've probably noticed one of
the most powerful forces for good or ill
in the world is corporations especially
large companies and right now we're
entering a time where there is a radical
shift happening in a number of aspects
of how business is being done both in
businesses themselves and just in
society in general one is that we're
moving from a time when there was an
abundance of resources that could be
used as raw inputs for business
operations and in the last hundred years
with the massive population growth of
humans to now beyond seven billion
people we're now living in a world where
many of those basic input into
manufacturing processes are becoming
increasingly scarce so this is a shift
in paradigm that's going to be required
for businesses to be viable and
resilient moving into the future now one
of the things that this book does that I
think is really nice is it explores the
big ships such as this one from
abundance to scarcity terms of resource
input and also it's adding other
systemic issues like climate change and
the need for social values to be
reflected in business practices for
people to trust companies there what
Andrew Winston does is he does he does a
service to people in business who want
to be part of the solution so if you
work in the business world and you have
a desire to help transform our system
meaning shift from an old economic
paradigm to a new one then this book
gives you a roadmap for how to do that
so among the things that I really like
in this book is the way that it shows
the business case for doing good in the
world in the business case for
sustainability so if you are working for
a large company and you need insights
into how to sell your CEO or your CFO on
the business practices that are going to
be necessary
for long term resilience of our
civilization then this book will show
you how to make the case that that same
set of solutions is also going to
business to succeed and make a lot of
money along the way see right now we're
in a time where we need to build an
entirely different way of operating in
the world and this includes everything
from energy systems to food production
to water supply to built environment to
transportation systems to information
technology and communications as well as
media production media communications
and just eat the list could go on and on
and every one of these domains there are
huge opportunities for new markets to be
created where people make money by
promoting Cradle to Cradle recycling of
resources where they reduce their carbon
footprint meaning that they're doing
less harm and even more good to help
with a climate disruption to help bring
climate disruption to an end or minimize
the harms that humanity will have to
face and so this is an area where
business has been slow to learn that it
actually has great opportunity to create
profit while doing good in the world and
if you want to understand how to do that
then this is one of the better books out
there so this is the big pivot by andrew
winston and i highly recommend it for
anyone who wants to use business to do
good in the world so there you go I hope
you can help use this knowledge to make
your business's better and make a
positive difference in the world thanks
a lot and every day